It was raining...
雨がふっていた
You're always reading that book, boy.
いつもその本を読んでるな　坊主
Is it that interesting?
そんなに面白いか
It's good.
面白い
I've read it many times now.
もう何度も読んでる
そんな話より面白い話が世の中にはごまんとあるぞ
There are so many more
stories out in the world
that are far more interesting
than what's in that book.
Where's Part Three?
その本　下巻はどうした
Part 2 of 3
下巻は持ってない
I don't have Part Three.
いくら探してもなかった
I've looked and looked,
but I've never found it.
それで得心がいったわ
Now it all makes sense.
That story's Part Three is
the worst of the worst.
その小説は下巻がとんでもなく最悪でな
You should consider yourself satisfied
with just the first two parts.
上巻と中巻だけで満足しておけ
それがお前の為だ
I'm saying this for your own good.
I'm afraid I can't do that.
そうもいかない
Then you write it.
ならばお前が書け
自分が書く？
Me, write?
それが唯一その小説を完璧なままにしておく方法だ
That's the only way you can
keep that story perfect.
Part 2 of 3
小説を書くことは人間を書くことだ
To write a story is
to write about a person,
どう生きて　どう死ぬべきかということをな
and how that person should live and die.
From what I've seen,
you have the qualifications.
儂の見たところ　お前にはその資格がある
Who are you?
あなたはいったい誰なんです
Me?
儂か
My name is...
儂の名は…
Are you awake, Odasaku?
目覚めたかい　織田作
How do you feel?
気分は？
I feel like I'm experiencing
all the hangovers I'll have
向こう五十年の二日酔いをまとめて受け取っている気分だ
in the next fifty years
all at the same time.
I saw Ango at the place you told me about.
お前に云われた場所で　安吾に会った
So Ango was there, like I suspected.
矢張り安吾はあの場所にいたのだね
Yeah.
ああ
He vanished into the dark
with soldiers in black.
黒ずくめの兵士達と闇に消えた
Sounds like black special ops.
差し当たり　黒の特殊部隊といったところだね
どうやら起こっている現象は二つに分けられるようだ
It seems recent events can be
divided into two categories.
Are they a separate organization from Mimic?
奴らとミミックは別組織なのか
They're different.
別だよ
ただ　黒の特殊部隊のほうは当面無視していい
But we can pretty much ignore the
black special ops guys for now.
Mimic is the more dangerous enemy.
矢張り危険なのはミミックだ
市内で起きている抗争に　芥川君を初めとする武闘派構成員で対抗しているけど
Akutagawa-kun and other
combat squad members
are dealing with conflicts in the city,
こちらは敵の長が使う異能力さえわかっていないんだ
but we don't even know what the
enemy leader's ability is.
分が悪い
We're at a disadvantage.
その芥川という男は確かお前の部下だったな
That Akutagawa is one of your
subordinates, isn't he?
I heard his ability has high
offensive capabilities.
かなり攻撃的な異能力を持っていると聞いたが
彼は鞘のない刀剣だよ
He's a naked sword without a scabbard.
I'm sure he'll become the strongest
gifted mafia member in the near future but,
遠からずマフィア最強の異能力者になるだろうが
right now, he needs someone to
teach him how to sheathe his blade.
今は誰かが刃の仕舞い方を教えなくちゃならない
話が逸れたね
Sorry, that was a tangent.
This morning, the council of five
top executives convened.
今朝　五大幹部会が招集され
ポートマフィアの全戦力を以て　ミミックを迎撃することが決定された
They made a decision to attack Mimic
with everything
the Port Mafia can muster.
Just now,
つい先刻　芥川君を含む私の部下が奇襲を受け
my subordinates, including Akutagawa-kun,
were hit by a surprise attack.
They're still fighting at the art museum.
今も美術館で抗争を…
織田作？
Odasaku?
まさか行くのかい
You're not serious about going, are you?
全戦力を以て迎撃するんだろう
We're hitting them with
everything we've got, right?
I didn't think you'd be interested in conflict, since you don't kill people.
人殺しをしない織田作は抗争なんて興味ないと思っていたよ
ない
I'm not.
じゃあなんで
Then why?
I've acquired a lot of debts in my life.
借りの多い人生だからな
部下が苦戦中なら　扶けが必要だ
If your subordinates are in a tough spot,
they need help.
You should forget about your debts.
借りなんて忘れてしまえばいい
Episode 15
Some Day in a
Room with a
Seaside View
No one remembers what you owe to them.
相手だって　何を貸したかなんて　覚えちゃいないさ
銃など愚者の戎具
Guns are the weapons of fools.
All too weak.
あまりにも非力
So you're the one they speak of...
The gifted one in black.
貴君か
黒衣の異能力者と云うのは
何者だ
Who are you?
My name is Gide.
乃公の名はジイド　ミミックを束ねる者だ
I am the leader of Mimic.
雑魚を何人倒そうと　あの人は僕を認めぬ
He will never acknowledge me,
no matter how many underlings I defeat.
手合わせ願おう
I'd like to challenge you.
一つ聞く
I'd like to ask a question.
Is your ability sufficient to release
our souls from original sin?
貴君の異能力は我らの魂を原罪から解放するに足る力か
Want to find out?!
試してみるか
You're not getting away!
逃すか
It seems you are not the one.
貴君ではないようだ
Impossible!
莫迦な
Is this an ability?!
これは異能力か
Bastard!
貴様
Can you read my moves?!
僕の動きが読めるとでもいうのか
In a few more years,
あと数年もあれば　我々の望みを叶える異能力者になっていたやもしれぬが
you may have grown powerful
enough to grant our wish,
but we cannot wait.
待てぬ
殺せ
Kill me.
Defeat means death.
敗残兵は去るのみ
I regret that I could not
be the enemy you wanted.
貴様の求める敵になってやれず　すまなかった
Farewell.
さらばだ
足を撃たれたのか
Did you get shot in the leg?
Hey!
おい
貴様　何をする
What do you think you're doing?!
降ろせ　降ろせ
Let me down!
Let me go!
俺は織田作之助
I'm Oda Sakunosuke.
I heard about you from
Dazai and came to help.
太宰に話を聞いて扶けに来た
貴様の名は太宰さんから聞いている
I've heard of you from Dazai-san.
You're one of the lower-ranking members.
一介の下級構成員だ
That's right.
そうだ
そしてあの人の友人だと聞いた
And I heard you're a friend to him.
Is that true?
誠か
その手の言葉は軽々しく口にしない主義だ
I have a policy of not using
that word lightly.
太宰さんは云った
Dazai-san said
僕は百年経っても貴様には勝てぬと
I wouldn't stand a chance against you,
not in a hundred years.
仲間割れをしている時間はない
Now's not the time to be having a falling out.
何故だ
Why...
Why doesn't Dazai-san...
何故太宰さんは僕を
Are you the same?!
貴様も…
Sorry.
悪いな
お前に期待している友の為にも
I have to bring you back,
especially for a friend who
has high hopes for you.
必ず連れて帰らねばならん
予感があった
I did have a premonition.
何の話だ
What are you talking about?
この国で　その異能力者に会えるという予感だ
I had a premonition that I'd be able to
meet the person I seek in this country.
乃公はジイド
I am Gide.
我ら幽霊の魂を解き放つ者を探しに来た
I came here in search of the one who can
release the souls of ghosts like us.
知人の葬儀業者なら　割引料金で紹介できるが
I can get you a discount with an
undertaker I know if you want.
必要ない
There is no need.
たった今見つけたからな
I just found the one we were looking for.
なんだ
What?
どうした
What's the matter?
I haven't even fired a single round.
乃公はまだ銃を撃ってすらいないぞ
What did you do?!
何をした
I just saw a future where you
would dodge to the right.
乃公には今　貴君が右に避ける未来が観えた
それに合わせて狙いを修正した
Therefore, I adjusted my aim.
だが貴君はその未来を観て方向を修正した
But you saw that future,
so you adjusted as well.
Which I also saw.
それも乃公には観えた
The ability to see a few seconds into the
future if you are to be in any danger...
数秒後に起こる自分の危機を観る能力
乃公もまた貴君と同じことができる
I can do what you can do.
俺達の持つ未来観測能力は万能だ
The predictive ability
we have is omnipotent.
You are the only one who can
kill me and end this war.
貴君だけが乃公を葬り　この抗争を止められる
If you are one of the Port Mafia,
貴君がポートマフィアの人間なら　敵の長たる乃公を撃つことこそ本懐
killing me, the enemy leader,
must be your greatest desire.
断る
No thanks.
I'm only here to help one of my own.
俺は仲間を扶けに来ただけだ
What?
なに
You're not one of the mafia?
貴君はマフィアではないのか
マフィアも色々だ
There are different types in the mafia.
銃は人を殺す道具だ
Guns are tools for murder!
And this is a war zone!
そしてここは戦場だ
戦うことに興味がない
I'm not interested in fighting.
な…
What I'm interested in is living.
俺が興味があるのは　生きることだ
There is nothing more important
in life than death!
死よりも重要な生など存在しない
そうだ　それでいい
Good, that's how it should be...
なに
What?!
Are you refusing to fight me, then?
あくまで本気で戦う心算はないと
俺には殺しをしない理由がある
There is a reason I don't kill.
Look elsewhere.
余所を当たってくれ
何故だ
Why?!
My subordinates and I have been
wandering the whole world like ghosts,
乃公と部下達は死に値する場所を求め　死霊のように世界を彷徨った
looking for a place worthy of our deaths.
You are our only wish.
貴君が唯一の望みなのだ
戦ってくれ
Fight me!
でなければ…
If you refuse—
俺がお前の願いを聞けないのは
The reason I can't do as you wish
夢があるからだ
is because I have a dream.
いつかポートマフィアを辞めて　何でもできる身になった時
Some day when I can quit the
Port Mafia and become a free man,
海の見える部屋で　机に座って
I want to sit down at a desk in a room
where I can see the sea, and...
Then you write it.
ならばお前が書け
That's the only way you can
keep that story perfect.
それが唯一その小説を完璧にしておく方法だ
小説家になりたいんだ
I want to become a writer.
I want to throw the gun aside,
銃を捨て　紙とペンだけを持って
and only have pen and paper.
One man told me that to write
a story is to write a person.
ある人が「小説を書くことは人間を書くことだ」と云った
人の命を奪う者に人生を書くことはできない
A man who takes lives
cannot write about lives.
That's why I won't kill.
だから俺は人を殺さない
And that's the reason why you
refuse to enter our battle?
それが我々の戦場に登ってこない理由なのか
それがお前の答えか
So that's your answer?
That's right.
そうだ
Stop!
やめろ
防弾内衣か
A bullet-proof vest.
生きているが故の痛みだな
That pain that is a privilege of the living.
It's something we lost long ago.
とうの昔に失ったものだ
We are already dead.
我らはもう死んでいる
We're just soulless husks
being controlled by ghosts.
魂のない肉体を　亡霊が操っているに過ぎない
お前は死んでいない
You're not dead.
I don't know what happened
to you in the past,
過去に何があったか知らないが
自分の死に方をゆっくり考えることはできる
but you can still think
about how you want to die.
Why won't you understand?!
何故わからない
You are the only...
貴君だけが唯一の…
貴君は乃公を殺さない
You will not kill me.
乃公の望みを理解していないからだ
That's because you don't understand my wish.
そして乃公も今は貴君を殺さない
And I won't kill you right now,
貴君だけが我らを浄火の戦場に導く者だからだ
because you are the only one who can guide
us to the battlefield of purification.
貴君に本当の我らを理解させてやる
I will make you understand
who we really are.
そうすればわかるだろう
Then you will understand
that, between the two of us,
there can be only one.
貴君と乃公のどちらかが死ぬしかないということが
You should look forward to it.
楽しみにしていろ
夜はいい
The night is a good time.
マフィアの時間だ
It's a time that belongs to the Port Mafia.
What now?
これからどうする
どうしたもんかねぇ
I don't know.
それにしても災難だったね
That was quite some trouble
you got into, though.
敵の首領に会うなり　熱烈な求愛を受けるなんて
Who would've thought that the enemy leader
you'd just met would turn
into such an earnest suitor?
They're weird, looking for war so that they
can find a place worthy of their deaths.
死に値する場所を探す為に戦場を求めるなど　変な奴らだ
そうかい
Are they?
死に方に工夫を凝らしたいなんて　私にはない発想だよ
Their wish to be creative about their deaths
is something I hadn't thought about.
How long will this conflict last?
この抗争はいつまで続く
Mimic's soldiers aside,
ミミックの兵士はともかく　指揮官の異能力は厄介だね
their leader's ability is a nuisance.
奇襲が効かない
Surprise attacks won't work.
That means we need inside info.
となると　内部情報が必要だ
Any leads you can think of?
心当たりはあるかい
Only Ango.
安吾しかいない
I agree.
私も同意見だね
I wonder if there's some
way we can find Ango.
安吾を探す方法はないものかなぁ
There is.
ある
There is?
あるのか
To be more precise,
正確に云えば　探し出す必要すらない
there is no need to find him.
Here?
ここか
他にあるかい
Where else?
やあ　どうも
Hey there.
I started without you.
お先にやってますよ
連絡くらいくれてもよかったんじゃないか
You could've called.
I had a hard time losing my tail.
尾行を撒くのに苦労しましてね
But today's fine.
でも今日は大丈夫です　ゆっくり飲める
I can spend as much time as I want here.
Well?
それで　どうしてここがわかったんです
How'd you know to find me here?
Just a hunch, I suppose.
なんとなく　ね
I'm lucky.
僕はついてる
I didn't think I could drink here again.
ここで飲めることはもうないと思っていました
潜入捜査官にしては　随分と感傷的じゃないか
You're pretty sentimental for a mole.
君はポートマフィアに入る前から　別の顔があった
Even before you joined the Port Mafia,
you had a different identity.
それは国の秘密機関　内務省異能特務課のエージェントとしての顔だ
And that's as a secret agent of the state.
You were an agent of the
Ministry of Internal Affairs'
gifted special operations division.
Your mission was to monitor the Port Mafia.
任務はポートマフィアの動向の監視
国内の異能力者を統括する秘密組織といえど
Though the division oversees
all gifted within the nation,
should there ever be an all-out
war with the Port Mafia,
ポートマフィアと全面戦争となれば　只では済まない
the division will suffer heavy casualties.
The division's primary purpose is to
manage, not annihilate, the gifted.
そもそも特務課の任務は異能力者の管理だ
殲滅じゃない
That's why they had an agent infiltrate the
Port Mafia and monitor their movements.
だからポートマフィア内にエージェントを潜入させ　動向を監視させていた
Then Mimic came up at the table.
そしてそこに　ミミックの話が持ち上がった
The gifted criminal organization
had been planning to enter Japan.
日本上陸を計画していた異能犯罪組織は特務課からしても頭の痛い存在だ
They were a headache for the division,
so the division decided to have you
monitor Mimic... as the Port Mafia's spy.
それで君にミミックの動向を探らせることにした　ポートマフィアの間諜としてね
薄給の国家公務員としては　まったく割りに合わない仕事でしたよ
As a lowly salaried government worker,
it was a job entirely above my pay grade.
So, in other words,
つまり安吾は
Ango wasn't a double agent,
but a triple agent.
二重間諜ではなく　三重間諜だったというわけか
Tell us about Mimic.
ミミックについて教えてくれ
I heard Gide and Odasaku-san traded blows.
ジイドと織田作さんが会敵したという情報が入りました
ジイドの異能力は見ましたか
Did you see Gide's ability?
I did.
見た
Gide is elusive, and his location
is never made known to us.
ジイドは神出鬼没で　居場所を悟らせません
The brass intends to let the
Port Mafia handle this case.
上はこの件を　完全にポートマフィアに投げる腹積もりです
そりゃあまた随分と虫のいい話だね
Well, that's very convenient for them.
けどポートマフィアにしたって　あの異能力を突破するのは難しいと思うよ
But even the Port Mafia would have a
hard time dealing with his ability.
Of course,
もちろん
一人の最下級構成員を除いて　だけど
that's if we don't consider a certain
lowest-ranking member in the organization.
俺の異能力も奴の異能力もほんの数秒先が予見できるに過ぎない
Both our abilities only entail looking
a few seconds into the future.
If push comes to shove,
結局のところ　勝敗は戦闘と射撃の技倆にかかってくる
the outcome will be dependent on
our skills in combat and shooting.
不確定要素は大きいでしょう
The unknown variables will matter a lot.
There's also "the singularity
of the ability" to consider.
異能力の特異点の問題もある
The singularity of the ability?
異能力の特異点？
Didn't something unusual happen when
you used your ability against Gide?
ジイドに対して異能力を使った時　いつもと違うことが起きませんでしたか
Yeah, it did.
ああ　起きた
複数の異能力が干渉し合うと
The government has observed that
when some abilities interact,
ごく稀にまったく予想もしなかった方向に異能力が暴走するという現象が
they may careen off into an entirely
unexpected direction in rare cases.
政府機関に拠って確認されています
I wasn't really supposed to tell you that.
今の話　本当はしてはいけないことになっています
It'd become a major issue if the brass were
to know that I am meeting you like this.
僕がこうして会っていることも　上層部に知られたら大問題になります
I'll have to go underground
for the time being.
当面は姿を隠さなくては
Well, well...
おやおや
You're talking as though you
will leave this place alive.
まるで自分が生きてここから出られるみたいな口ぶりだね
Are you planning to make this a war zone?
ここを戦場にする気か
It's my fault.
僕の所為ですね
I was wrong.
僕が間違っていた
I selfishly thought that here,
この場所だけは皆さんと立場を超えて会えるような気が勝手にしていました
I could actually meet with you two
without having to consider my position.
Ango.
安吾
私の気が変わらないうちに消えるんだ
Go before I change my mind.
別に悲しんでいるんじゃない
I'm not sad.
最初からわかっていたことだ
I knew this from the beginning.
安吾が特務課であろうとなかろうと
Whether you were with the gifted
special operations division or not,
失いたくないものは必ず失われる
anything I would never want
to lose is always lost.
It is a given that everything
that is worth wanting
求める価値のあるものは皆
手に入れた瞬間に失うことが約束されている
will be lost the moment I obtain it.
There's nothing worth pursuing at the
cost of prolonging a life of suffering.
苦しい生を引き延ばしてまで追い求めるものなんて　何もない
Dazai-kun, Odasaku-san...
太宰君　織田作さん
If there ever comes a time when the division
and the Port Mafia don't exist
いつか時代が変わって　特務課もポートマフィアもない
我々がもっと自由な立場になったら
and we all become freer men,
またここ…
let's come back here and—
云うな　安吾
Don't say it, Ango.
それ以上言うな
Don't say anything more.
What?
なんだ
Mister!
親爺さん
Kosuke!
幸介　克巳
Katsumi!
Yu!
優　真嗣
Shinju!
Sakura!
咲楽
A map?
地図
喉が痛かった
My throat hurt.
I couldn't breathe.
呼吸ができなかった
I heard someone screaming.
誰かの叫び声が聞こえた
I realized, because my throat hurt so much,
that I was the one who was screaming.
あまりに喉が激しく痛むので気付いた
叫んでいたのは　俺だった
Then you write it.
ならばお前が書け
That's the only way you can
keep that story perfect.
それが唯一その小説を完璧なままにしておく方法だ
I can't write it anymore.
もう書けない
I can no longer write a story.
俺はもう
小説を書くことはできない
Next Time: Episode 16
Bungo Stray Dogs
だが違うんだ
あいつはあまりに頭の切れるただの子供だ
暗闇の中で俺たちが見ている世界よりも
遥かに何もない虚無の世界で独り取り残され
ただ泣いている子供だ
今では　その孤独に土足で踏み込まなかったことを
少し後悔している
次回　文豪ストレイドッグス　第十六話
文豪ストレイドッグ